one of the most famous trends is
probably one you have heard of it's
Moore's law Moore's law roughly states
that every one-and-a-half to two years
we worked it twice the number of
transistors on the same chip area so
this is what technology improvement
promises to do as computer architects we
try to translate that into doubling the
processor speed every 18 to 24 months so
what we try to do is if the technology
can give us twice as many transistors we
try to translate that into doubling the
processor speed we also try to reduce
the energy per operation to about half
of what it was every 18 to 24 months
pretty much the transistors are now half
the sizes they used to be so we try to
translate that into using half as much
energy for the operation of the same
work and we try to double the memory
capacity every 18 to 24 months so we can
fit twice as many transistors on the
same chip area we try to translate that
into having twice as much memory if this
is a memory chip again note that this is
what the technology can be expected to
do and this is what architects are
expected to do with their technology
that way we can plan for what the
technology will be able to provide us
with and we know what the computer
market will expect from our future
computers